JAMES RUPA

Jamesrupa.com (347) 884-7771 jamesjrupa@gmail.com

Summary:

Future Software Engineer, currently majoring in Computer Science at Brooklyn College. Excellent creativity, critical thinking, and problem-solving skills. Able to multitask, adapt, and quickly learn something when needed. Previous experience with leadership, organization, and communication skills. Capable to work as part of a team, while taking individual responsibility.

- Programming Language: Python, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Java, Git
- Skills: Microsoft Suite, Linux, Eagle Scout with Silver Palms
- Bilingual English/Polish

Education:

BROOKLYN COLLEGE, CITY UNIVERISTY OF NEW YORK

B.S. Computer Science, Spring 2023 GPA: 3.6

Dean's List. Excelsior Scholarship, Peter F. Vallone Academic Scholarship, Computer Science Club

SCHOLARS' ACADEMY, HIGH SCHOOL

June 2019 Cumulative GPA: 4.0

Advanced Regents Diploma, Community Service Seal, National Honors Society, Swim Team Captain

Experience:

Hempstead Harbour Club, Launch Boat Operator

Glen Cove, NY

Spring 2021-Present

- Operating launch vessels coordinating the transportation of club members
- Maintained club with general upkeep activities
- Tracking member launch activity records daily

Hempstead Harbour Club, Junior Sailing Instructor

Glen Cove, NY

Summers 2017-2021

- Supervised over 60+ children (age of 8-15) focusing on sailing and regatta skill development
- Coached an advanced racing group of 10 sailors
- Attended weekly junior regattas each year during the months of July and August

National Park Service, Beach Lifeguard

Riis Park, NY

Summer 2020

- Observing and organizing the activity of swimmers on the beach
- Enforcing park policies and regulations
- Rescuing swimmers in distress and providing necessary emergency care

Python Coding Tutor

Queens, NY

Fall 2019-Spring 2020

- Privately tutored introductory level Python to middle school aged students
- Enhanced student learning by incorporating various instructional approaches
- Delivered weekly at-home assignments to further grasp concepts and allow for additional practice

Scholars' Academy High School, Teaching Assistant

Queens, NY

Fall 2018-Summer 2019

- Intro to Python Programming elective offered to 11th and 12th grade students
- Created weekly PowerPoint presentations and pop-up reviews for upcoming topics
- Worked alongside 30 students, helping and grading assignments throughout the school year

<u>Professional Development:</u>

NY Python Group Member, 2019 Tech Night Hackathon, 2018 StuyHacks Hackathon, 2018 Google Code-In Participant